DAYS!
It's warm...
（政(せい)）温かいな
Oh... It's the first time... I've felt this warmth...
そうか　初めてだ このぬくもりは
This is the first time... I've been hugged by someone like this.
誰かに
こうして抱きしめられるのは
初めてだ
I won't let them kill him...
（紫夏(しか)）
殺させない　この子は私が守る
I will protect this child!
（亜門(あもん)）ンンッ… まだかよ？
紫夏のヤツ 何やってんだ？
They're still not back?!
What is Xia doing?!
Sorry for the wait.
（紫夏）お待たせ！
（亜門）紫夏！ 遅(おせ)えよ
That took forever, Xia!
Hey, is the kid okay?
（江彰(こうしょう)）
おい！ そのガキ 大丈夫なのか？
フフッ… 大丈夫
He's okay.
He's all right now.
（紫夏）もう大丈夫
Binding Wish
The young boy, Zheng, fated from birth to become king, is being delivered to the State of Qin.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）大王となる宿命のもとに
生まれた少年 政を―
秦国(しんこく)に送り届ける
紫夏と その一行は
趙国(ちょうこく)の最後の関門を抜け
Zi Xia and her band of black marketeers had just gotten through the last gate of the State of Zhao,
一路 国境へと馬を走らせていた
and were running on horseback straight to the state border.
Okay! Okay! We're gonna make it!
（田慈(でんじ)）よし！ よし！
帰れる 秦国に帰れるぞ！
We're gonna make it to the State of Qin!
From running non-stop for days, the horses are pretty tired.
連日 走ってるせいで
馬も かなり疲れてやがる
That really did waste a lot of time...
さっきの時間の浪費が
やはり大きかったか
The State of Zhao has the best pursuers in all of China.
（亜門）趙国の追尾能力は中華一だ
もし俺たちのことが
バレてるとしたら そろそろ…
If they did find out about is, then it won't be long...
A sand cloud!
砂煙だ！
後方で砂煙が上がっている！
There's a sand cloud rising from the path behind us!
It's the mounted unit that's been pursuing us!
追っ手の騎馬隊だ！
（道剣(どうけん)）なに？
What?!
（単元(たんげん)）クッ… ここまで来て…
They've already caught up this much?!
Don't panic! They're still quite a ways behind us!
慌てるな！ まだ だいぶ後ろだ
Ready the weapons!
武器の準備をしろ！
戦いながらの逃走になるぞ！
We're going to fight while fleeing!
Lord Dao Jian, where is the rendezvous point?!
道剣どの 合流地は？
（道剣）松で囲まれた池のほとりだ
The bank of a pond surrounded by pine trees!
Chisong Pond?!
赤松(あかまつ)の池か
That's too far!
遠すぎる　赤松は国境の向こう側だ
Chisong is on the other side of the state border!
It can't be done.
ムリだ
そこまで騎馬隊からは逃げられん
We'll never evade the mounted unit all the way there!
Ya Men!
（江彰）亜門！
（亜門）おう！
Yeah?!
You haven't forgotten the promise we made when we were kids, right?!
ガキんときに決めた２人の約束
忘れてないだろうな？
ヘッ… 忘れるかよ
Like I could forget that.
The last one of us three to die will be Zi Xia!
（江彰･亜門）３人の中で
いちばん最後に死ぬのは紫夏
We're originally orphans that got adopted after all!
もともと拾われた命だしな
But from the moment we became black marketeers, we had to be prepared for something like this to happen!
闇商人やってる時点で いつか
こうなる覚悟はしてたけどよ
The only regret I have is that I could never make her mine.
あいつをモノに
できなかったことだけが心残りだ
せめて告白ぐらいしとくんだった
タハハハッ…
I wish I would've at least confessed to her at some point!
I did.
俺は したぜ
（亜門）えっ？
When I was 16, I asked her to marry me.
16んときに“結婚しろ”っつった
What?! And what happened?!
なに？ そ… それで？
She turned me down. She said she was gonna take over for dad.
あいつは断って
親父(おやじ)の後を継ぎやがった
プッ！
タハハッ… お前 フラれたのか
She blew you off, huh?!
うるせえ！
（亜門）…ていうか てめえ
Shut up!
And anyhow, I'm impressed ya kept somethin' major like that from me for so long!
そんな大事なこと
よくも今まで黙ってたな
（江彰）うるせえ！
てめえなんかに言うかよ
Shut up!
You're not one to talk!
（田慈）ハァ… ハァハァ…
No way...!
まさか…
The mounted unit!
騎馬隊だ！ 騎馬隊がいるぞ！
They're here!
Run, Zi Xia!
逃げろ！ 紫夏！
You traitors!
（騎兵）この国賊が！
Zi Xia!
紫夏！
Stay away from our general, you bastard!
ウチの大将に近づくな てめえ！
（紫夏）亜門！
Ya Men!
アアッ！
（亜門）単元！
Dan Yuan!
ヘヘッ…
やっぱ告白しときゃよかったよ
I really do wish I'd have confessed.
Zi Xia.
紫夏
So long!
あばよ
ウオーッ！
（紫夏）亜門！
Ya Men!
亜門！
クッ… くそー！
Goddammit!
Any sign of them?!
（兵士）それらしい気配はないか？
（見張り）
何も　砂煙ひとつ見えません
None!
I don't see a single cloud of dust!
Then just keep watching!
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）そのまま見張りを続けよ
騎馬隊は―
And be prepared for a mounted unit to come at any time!
いつでも出られる準備をしておけ
（部下）はっ！
Yes, sir!
Is this the end?
（道剣）これまでか…
Where are you going?
（亡霊Ａ）どこへ行く？
（亡霊Ｂ）お前の居場所など
どこにもないぞ
You don't belong anywhere.
You should just go to sleep.
（亡霊Ｄ）そのまま眠ればいい
楽になれるぞ
Everything will feel so much better.
（政）ハァ… アアッ…
ハァ…
W-Wait.
（幻影）
フフッ… 待てよ フフフフッ…
I know, Zheng.
俺は知っているぞ 政
I know that you're a member of the royal family, who was born in an enemy state and pelted with the malice of war.
王族の身でありながら敵国に生まれ
戦争の怨念にあたり
お前は
痛みを失うほどに心は内に籠もった
So much so that you shut your emotions down so deep that you lost even the ability to feel pain.
But you haven't become merely a soulless doll.
だが お前は ただ魂の抜けた人形に
なっていたわけじゃない
ひたすら自問自答を繰り返していた
You've been doing nothing but answering your own questions over and over...
About war, people, kingdoms, and kings.
戦争と人と…
国と王について
That's right.
そのとおりだ
And so now, you've drawn a fearsome king's path in your heart, right?
（幻影）そして今 お前は胸の中に
恐ろしい王の道を描いているな？
A perilous road no one has ever walked before...
いまだかつて
何者も歩んでいない恐ろしい道を
フフフッ… やめておけ
Give it up.
It would be so much easier to just sleep here with us...
今ここで我らと眠りに就くほうが
ずっと楽だぞ
Stop your meaningless struggling.
ムダなあがきは よせ
I had sunk into the darkness, but this person has reached her hand out to me.
（政）闇に沈んでいた俺に
この人は手を差し伸べてくれた
Her strong hand...
（政）力強い手
もはや迷うことも臆することもない
I no longer feel any hesitation or fear.
I will go to the State of Qin and become king!
俺は秦国へ帰り 王となる
It will be a rigorous path that will call death towards you...
周りに死を呼ぶ過酷な道だ
You'll suffer...
苦しむぞ…
I am prepared for that.
覚悟のうえだ　俺は必ず…
I have to...
You're awake?
お目覚めになりましたか
（政）ああ
Yes.
Xia... Your arm...
紫夏 その腕は…
There are stray arrows coming, so please lower your head.
流れ矢が来ますので
頭を下げておいてくださいね
You really woke up at the worst time.
最悪のときに起きちまったな
Dao Jian, how far is it to the rendezvous point?!
道剣 合流地までは？
（道剣）恐らく およそ二刻(ふたこく)
Most likely about two ke.
( A "ke" is about 15 minutes. )
しかし 恐れながら
あと半刻と もちそうにありません
But I fear we may not be able to last another quarter ke.
If the mounted unit catches us, it's over.
騎馬隊に捕まっちまったら
どうしようもねえ
It's hard to accept, but I think this is the end.
（江彰）悔しいが これまでだ
Don't give up!
諦めるな！
We're not out of arrows and our horses are still running!
矢も尽きていない　馬も走っている
まだ うなだれるときではないぞ！
It's not time to be hanging our heads yet!
今は １歩でも
秦国に近づくことだけを考えろ
What we have to be thinking about is getting as close to the State of Qin as possible!
What's with this kid all of a sudden?
何だ？ こいつ　いきなり…
うむ…
Zi Xia, there's a chance that the soldiers at the rendezvous point might be coming this way.
紫夏 合流地の兵が
動いてくる可能性だってある
早々に諦めるなんて
お前らしくないぞ
It's not like you to give up so quickly.
You said you were gonna bring me to the State of Qin, right?
俺を秦国へ連れていくと
言っただろう
Sounds like you really have woken up, huh?
本当に目覚められたみたいですね
It's all because you extended your hand out to me.
お前が
手を差し伸べてくれたおかげだ
（天布(てんふ)）ハハハッ… いきなり
張り切りだしましたぞ あの男
That man's suddenly gotten really enthusiastic.
（冬顔(とうがん)）フフッ… 秦国の山猿が
我らの力を見せてやろう
Damn State of Qin monkeys.
Let me show you our power.
All archers, fire at once!
一点掃射！
（騎兵たち）オーッ！
Dao Jian.
道剣！
（矢の刺さる音）
I-I'm chagrined...
む… 無念
L-Lord Zheng, forgive me...
せ… 政さま お許しを…
Dao Jian!
道剣！
Dammit!
くそ！
（幻影）周りに死を呼ぶ過酷な道だ
It will be a rigorous path that will call death towards you...
Dammit!
Zi Xia
くそー！
（床を殴る音）
うん？ あれは…
Hm? That's...
Reporting!
（見張り）報告！
We knocked off all of those State of Qin guys.
秦国のヤツらは全て倒した
あとは商人２人と政のみ
Now all that's left are the two merchants and Zheng!
We'll rip those two traitors limb from limb and put them on display!
（冬顔）国賊２人は
八つ裂きにして野にさらせ！
We'll bring back Zheng's head, so don't harm his face!
政は首を持ち帰る！
顔は傷つけるな
胴より下は ２人と同様だ！
Treat anything below his neck the same as those two!
Father, just like how you saved us,
父上…
あなたが我々を救ってくれたように
私も
この子を救おうと思ったのですが
I thought I could save this boy, but...
It seems so hard.
難しそうです
I overestimated my own power...
自分の力を過信していた
and got Ya Men and Jiang Zhang involved...
亜門と江彰を巻き込んで…
I guess saving a person's life isn't that simple.
やはり 人の命を救うことは
そんなに簡単ではない
Now that Ya Men sacrificed himself, I don't feel like I can save anyone anymore.
亜門が犠牲になった今
自分が助かろうなんて思いません
But if I can at least just save this boy...
だけど せめて この子だけでも…
If I can connect this life you gave me to another...
いただいた命を次につなげなければ
A sand cloud!
（紫夏）砂煙！
Hurry!
急げ！ 必ず政さまを―
We must bring Lord Zheng to Xiangyang at any cost!
咸陽(かんよう)まで お連れするのだ！
（部下たち）はっ！
Yes, sir!
Lord Zheng, please lend me a hand.
政さま 御をお願いします
しっかり手綱を持って
Hold on to the reins tightly.
Understand?
いいですか？
御には集中が必要です
You will need heavy concentration for this.
So make sure not to look behind you.
絶対に 後ろを見ないように
Zi Xia, what are you going to do?
紫夏 何をする気だ？
We'll give everything we have to the very end.
（紫夏）最後まで力を尽くすんです
And never give up!
諦めずに
Zi Xia!
紫夏…
ハッ… あれは…
Ah, that's...
The soldiers from the rendezvous point are heading this way!
合流地の兵が向かってきている
Can we make it?!
（政）間に合うか？
ウッ！
（紫夏）江彰！
Jiang Zhang!
亜門みてえに
カッコよくは逝(い)けねえみてえだな…
Looks like I'm not going out in a cool way like Ya Men did...
But...
けど…
For an orphaned life that was saved, this is plenty...
拾われた命にしちゃ 上出来だ
最後まで
ホレた女のそばにいられたからよ
because I was able to be with the woman I loved to the very end.
Zi Xia! Stay alive as long as you can!
紫夏！ 少しでも長く生きろよ！
Jiang Zhang!
江彰！
江彰ーっ！
Jiang Zhang!
Shit!
くそ！
I'm sorry... Jiang Zhang... Ya Men...
（紫夏）ごめん 江彰 亜門…
（泣き声）
I'm sorry I dragged the two of you into this...
私が２人を巻き込んでしまった
Good!
よ～し　あとは政と女１人だ！
Now all that's left are Zheng and the woman!
私も すぐに…
I'll be with you soon...
（騎兵）ハハハハッ…
あの女 細腕で弓を引くつもりか
Does that woman think she can use a bow with those slender arms?!
That woman's an archer!
（冬顔）
あの女 弓使いだ　侮るな！
Don't underestimate her!
That board's in the way! Move around to the sides!
（冬顔）板がジャマだ　側面に回れ
（騎兵）はっ！
Yes, sir!
Got you!
（騎兵）もらった！
Tian Bu!
天布！
（天布）はっ！
Zi Xia!
紫夏！
（紫夏）見るな！
Don't look!
Zi...
Not yet...
That's enough! Just sit right there!
もういい　そのまま じっとしてろ
（紫夏）えっ？
Please, stay still!
頼むから じっとしていてくれ
L-Lord Dong Yan!
と… 冬顔さま！
前方に砂煙が上がっております！
There is a sand cloud up ahead!
A mounted unit from the State of Qin, eh?!
秦国の騎馬隊か！ 政を迎えに
国境を越えてきおったな？
So they crossed the state border to get Zheng, did they?!
But they're still far away!
だが まだ遠い　遊びは終わりだ！
It's time to stop playing!
馬車に乗り移り
政の首を取ってこい！
Board that carriage and take Zheng's head!
Yes, sir!
Why?
なぜだ？ なぜ そこまで…
Why are you going so far?
When I was young, my life was saved by a complete stranger.
（紫夏）私も幼いころ
赤の他人に命懸けで助けられた
And when I was 10, that man died trying to save yet another person!
その人は 私が10歳のとき
また別の人間を救おうとして
命を落とした
オリャー！
In that man's dying moments, he screamed for me not to die.
その人の死に際 私は
“死なないでくれ”と泣き叫んだ
And I haven't still haven't done a single thing to repay the debt he gave me!
“受けた恩に対し 私は まだ
何ひとつ返せていない”と
But that man...
しかし その人は…
Favors should always be passed on to another person.
（父親）恩恵は全て 次の者へ
My life was saved by the lives of several people as well.
（父親）私の命も
幾人かの命によって救われてきた
I've intended to pay back that entire debt to you guys.
その恩を余さず
お前たちに注いだつもりだ
Zi Xia, if you're able to do something for someone else in the future,
紫夏… お前が この先
他人のために何かできたら
それは
私にとっても大きな意味を持つ
that would mean the world to me.
No matter how small they are...
どんなに些細(ささい)なことでも
pass on favors to someone else.
受けた恩恵を次の者へ
フフフッ… そういうものだ 紫夏
That's how they work, Zi Xia.
If you do that...
そうやって…
Out of the way!
（騎兵）どけ！
Zi Xia!
紫夏！
（紫夏）見るな！
Don't look!
If you do that... then people... will be bound to one another...
（紫夏）そうやって…
そうやって 人は つながっていく
That is what I was taught.
（紫夏）私は そう教えられてきた
So... So that's why you helped me...?
（政）だから… だから 俺を…
That's part of it.
（紫夏）それもあります
でも それだけじゃない
But that's not all...
I wanted to see the moon I saw with you that day again....
（紫夏）あの日見た あの月を
もう一度 あなたと…
I won't let you... kill this boy.
この子は…
殺させない！
ええい！ 何をしている？ 殺せ！
（紫夏）殺させない！
What are you doing?!
Kill them!
I won't let you!
There they are!
いたぞ！ 政さま！
Lord Zheng!
Zi Xia! It's the State of Qin soldiers!
紫夏！
秦国の兵だ！ 助けが来たぞ！
They're here to save us!
（冬顔）
チッ… 女はいい　政を射(う)て！
Forget the woman, shoot Zheng!
頑張れ 紫夏！ もう少しだ！
Hang in there, Zi Xia! We're almost there!
やれー！
Do it!
Zi Xia!
紫夏！
What is that woman?!
（騎兵）何だ この女！
Kill him!
（冬顔）殺せ！
Lord Zheng!
政さま！
Zi...
紫夏ーっ！
Zi Xia!
ハァ… 政さま…
Lord... Zheng...
What is it?
何だ？
Are you... unhurt?
（紫夏）おケガはありませんか？
Yeah, I'm fine.
ああ 大丈夫だ
お前のおかげで 俺は秦へ帰れる
Thanks to you, I'm gonna make it home to Qin.
Thanks to you, I'm gonna become king.
（政）
お前のおかげで 俺は王になる
I'd feel bad... if you forgot about Dao Jian... and the others...
道剣どのたちのことも
忘れては かわいそう
Yeah. You're right.
ああ そうだな
Dao Jian, Dan Yuan, Tian Ci, Ya Men, Jiang Zhao...
道剣 単元 田慈 亜門 江彰
みんなのおかげだ
It was thanks to all of you.
Lord Zheng...
政さま
（政）うん？
Due to the bad luck of your birth,
（紫夏）
あなたは生まれの不運により…
およそ王族が歩まぬ道を歩まされた
you walked a path that almost no member of a royal family has walked...
But, because of those difficult experiences, there is no person like you who will become a king.
ですが…
あなたほどつらい経験をして
王になる方は…
ほかにいません
So... I'm sure...
（紫夏）だから きっと…
You will... become a king greater than any other.
あなたは
誰よりも偉大な王になれます
Zi Xia! Dammit...
紫夏！ くそ…
くそー！
Dammit!
（紫夏）政さま…
Lord Zheng... your face...
お顔を…
Your eyes... are no longer...
もう目が…
（紫夏）
ああ… つきものは落ちましたなぁ
It looks like the moon has set.
瞳が なんとも…
Your eyes are... so beautiful...
美しい…
Zi Xia!
（政）紫夏ーっ！
Broken Love
End